<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-11-10T19:19:08-07:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jason’s Basecamp</title><subtitle>I am a person who is passionate about education. I enjoy inspiring people around me and taking in the knowledge that they have to share. Life isn’t always easy and we all have struggles, some more than others, but with a little understanding we can help each other overcome situations in order to succeed. This perhaps is why I enjoy being an educator.</subtitle><author><name>Jason</name></author><entry><title type="html">Tell a Story in Ten Frames</title><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/04/03/mini-storything-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tell a Story in Ten Frames" /><published>2021-04-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/04/03/mini-storything-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/04/03/mini-storything-5.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty straightforward, lightweight individual assignment. Tell a story using either 10 still images, 10 short video segments, or a combination of both. You choose the topic, the characters, etc. You can use any tool you’d like to achieve it–slideshows, collage, video, PowerPoint, or something else. Once you’re done, post it to the # Mini-things channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for a story in ten frames came together organically. As I was thinking through initial ideas, I became aware that this project lends itself to make some very complex stories. I was thinking, children’s books are illustrated in ten frames; people purchase homes in ten frames; most magazines, news, or online articles might not even make ten frames… So, I dialed it back. Well, at least I thought I did until I started producing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for “Meditations” came to me in the park. I thought I was going in one direction, but after some time outdoors, I ended up here. The story itself is loose, and I think it plays to the soundtrack and the essence of mediation… let yourself go and leave the world behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start things out, I first located media resources. After I knew media was available, I started producing. I first needed to sync up the original video with the new soundtrack. I imported both of these into Adobe Premiere. I cut the soundtrack to a start and end, then started trimming down the video. I started at the beginning, slowly modifying along the way. I spent some quality time in the first minute of the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soundtrack lends itself to have visual emphasis, so that was a piece of the challenge - syncing the sounds and sights up. I thought of this during the creative process. I went through the audio track and placed markers at points of emphasis throughout the soundtrack. I then adjusted the video timings using the “rate adjustment” tool. The markers were used as markers or guides to sync everything. The video was extended and shorted as need, even tossed some parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While adjusting the video, I noticed that there were some slow zooms in and out. This would cause issues with a mask unless I matched them. So, I went through and placed markers on the video denoting zooms. While doing this, I located a frame to export to Photoshop to create the image mask. In Photoshop, I outlined the person, and filled it in black, and then exported the image mask back into Premiere. I then layered, masked, and synced zooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then imported the ten frames and synced those to the soundtrack using the markers created earlier. I circled back to adjust the opacity to the video changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and early in the process, I created the title sequence - as short as it is; and then crated the credits to close out the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time--stretch&quot;&gt;Time &amp;amp; Stretch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project took 8 hours. I anticipated 4 hours. As the creative process goes, once I started remixing the original video and mixing in the original music, new ideas came into play. Throughout the many projects up to this point, each has allowed me to develop and learn new techniques. This project allowed me to combine multiple techniques, from photoshop to premiere. It is empowering when the tools facilitate the creative process and are not a barrier. I would have liked to experiment and try to implementing a “glitch” technique into one of my next projects. This one has a lot already going on… I even reversed a couple of videos - forward then backwards - that was fun. Still working to get a hang of the image masks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/&quot;&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Premiere Pro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attributions&quot;&gt;Attributions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by Lusine from YouTube &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=10Jg_25ytU0&quot;&gt;Just A Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music by Jon Hopkins from SoundCloud - &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/jonhopkins/1-2-singing-bowl-ascension&quot;&gt;1/2 Singing Bowl (Ascension) (Excerpt)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by PixaBay  from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/time-lapse-of-cumulus-clouds-856171/&quot;&gt;Time Lapse Of Cumulus Clouds&lt;/a&gt; CCO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by PixaBay from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/reflection-of-tree-at-night-854576/&quot;&gt;Reflection Of Tree At Night&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by Miriam Espacio from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/time-lapse-of-night-sky-1877846/&quot;&gt;Time Lapse Of Night Sky&lt;/a&gt; CCO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by Jyoti Pur from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/rain-and-winds-video-footage-on-a-stormy-day-3925550/&quot;&gt;Rain And Winds Video Footage On A Stormy Day&lt;/a&gt; CCO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by Taryn Elliott from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/aerial-footage-of-a-beach-7046645/&quot;&gt;Aerial footage of a Beach&lt;/a&gt; CCO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by Ruvim Miksanskiy from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/bird-s-eye-view-of-ocean-waves-1918465/&quot;&gt;Bird’s Eye View of Ocean Waves&lt;/a&gt; CCO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by Distill from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/time-lapse-video-of-aurora-borealis-852435/&quot;&gt;Time Lapse Video Of Aurora Borealis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by Louai Munajim from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/time-lapse-video-of-the-starry-night-sky-5943738/&quot;&gt;Time Lapse Video Of The Starry Night Sky&lt;/a&gt; CCO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by PixaBay from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/time-lapse-video-of-sunrise-by-the-sea-854638/&quot;&gt;Time Lapse Video Of Sunrise By The Sea&lt;/a&gt; CCO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by Madison Inouye from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/silhouette-of-grass-2097417/&quot;&gt;Silhouette Of Grass&lt;/a&gt; CC0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video by GamOl from Pexels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/video/landscape-nature-sky-night-4182910/&quot;&gt;Not Titled&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jason</name></author><category term="learnings" /><summary type="html">Assignment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Day in the Life</title><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/28/alternate-media-project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Day in the Life" /><published>2021-03-28T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-03-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/28/alternate-media-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/28/alternate-media-project.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use a tool, format or combination from above and create a media item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topic: Illustrate a day in the life in the year 2031 or 2051 of one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;K-12 Student (pick the grade)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;College Student&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adult learner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no predefined time limit on this assignment. Each tool and format is different and the outcomes will vary. The time should be appropriate to that of the tool and the effectiveness of the final product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learningexperience&quot;&gt;Learning/Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found this topic extremely challenging. With every class - in the LDT Program - I am being introduced to new technology, issues, and theories that are in our educational environment. As I move through the program, I am also considering where I might end up working in education. I’m probably overthinking the assignment but in a sense, it is a very real assignment - as we are active participants in the future of education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attempted an overly elaborate story and I keep getting stuck in the dystopian reality of inequality, injustice, and surveillance… but also dreaming about all the potential for emerging technologies (AR &amp;amp; AI), media, mobile. So, rather than focusing on just the day, I ended up creating a thorough backstory to lead to the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, I had to construct a timeline based story for 2051:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8:00 AM - Student wakes, and their IoT devices prepare them there required nourishments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9:00 AM - A self-driven automobile picks up student and brings them to a learning compound - that is within their community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9:30 AM - They check in with an Artificial Intelligence Machine to receive daily assignments. Daily assignments are generated by students’ interests and send them to interact with others - virtually. Assignments are multimodality (audio, text, video) and are interchangeable between modes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so on… but I keep getting hung up on filling in the backstory. So that ultimately became a central piece for this project. I hope you enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;successes&quot;&gt;Successes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shorthand is limited in what the software allows the user to produce. Knowing this now, I know a lot more pre-production work must take place to make spectacular scrollytelling stories happen. Examples, pre-producing audio and visual (video, photos, illustrations). However, learning that the Shorthand is a scrolling website builder that focuses on interactions to create engaging stories, I think I made something worth reading. I do think the available section templates are easy to use, and with an understanding of the tool could produce content that is more interactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;struggles&quot;&gt;Struggles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never used Shorthand and misunderstood what capabilities it provides. I thought creating interactive stories was the tool’s strength, and unless I am misusing it, it appears to just assemble your pre-produced works into a scrollytelling site - similar to Adobe Spark. Shorthand is limited in what sections are offered and has no easy way of shifting text or images from one section to the next or altering these pre-made sections. So once it’s in, that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Illustrator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shorthand.com&quot;&gt;ShortHand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attributions&quot;&gt;Attributions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/video/under-ais-watchful-eye-china-wants-to-raise-smarter-students/C4294BAB-A76B-4569-8D09-32E9F2B62D19.html&quot;&gt;Under AI’s Watchful Eye, China Wants to Raise Smarter Students&lt;/a&gt; via WSJ Videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@dole777?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;dole777&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/tennessee-governor-vote-no-on-school-vouchers&quot;&gt;Vote NO on School Vouchers&lt;/a&gt; via Change.org&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/guide-net-neutrality/&quot;&gt;The WIRED Guide to Net Neutrality&lt;/a&gt; via Wired&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rjLVCpE3kuw&quot;&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/a&gt; via YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://artsandculture.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Arts &amp;amp; Culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hitrecord.org/records/1328421&quot;&gt;HITRECORD Branding&lt;/a&gt; via #hitRECord&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vyond.com&quot;&gt;Vyond Interactive Videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://er.educause.edu&quot;&gt;EDUCAUSE Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jason</name></author><category term="learnings" /><summary type="html">Assignment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zoom Goldberg Machine</title><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/27/mid-storything-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zoom Goldberg Machine" /><published>2021-03-27T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-03-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/27/mid-storything-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/27/mid-storything-3.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Produce and contribute a Zoom-video for a collective class project that will be publicly shared. This is a project we have been trying to figure out for awhile. This is our inaugural effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requirements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Record your own Zoom segment of a Zoom Goldberg Machine, like above. Use a ball or any common moving object to trigger three or more reactions as it moves from left to right.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The first item must intersect with multiple other items, and send a final exit-item off-screen - -&amp;gt; to the next Zoomer. For the sake of consistency we are encouraging you to use one of the following for your exit-item: white ping-pong ball, white golf ball, toilet paper roll, paper towel roll, light bulb, crunched-up paper, an orange, a banana, or a pencil.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does a person make a chain-reaction machine with items and the space available at home. I thought up many contraptions to move a ball about, but each was one-step. When I thought about moving to the next step, I no longer had room. I was also struggling thinking of anything that would create a substantial video. So, instead I decided to take the “Zoom” aspect and run with it. Creating multiple independent machines, that when connected through a zoom-like video conference, it would appear as a digital chain reaction. I know this is part of the larger plan, but hey, I made something fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of brainstorming! I started by location scouting to find some areas outdoors to build some Rube Goldberg machines, but then I didn’t have any materials with me, poor planning. So the next venture I brought limited supplies to begin simply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first round of recording, I realized that each shot was going to need to be from certain angles, in order to have a fluid motion presented on screen. So I recaptured some elements from multiple angles and thought it would provide options during editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter editing. As I was going through the source materials, I started to sequence the machines together. While doing this, I also made text frames with notes about what should come next and a direction of movement. Of course I needed to reshoot pieces and as these moved along, I also had to build more machines to fill the next frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the process was started, linking one frame to the next, it became less of a challenge and more hands one creativity. With more time, I could keep going, and refine each machines movements and fill in more blanks, but am pretty happy with the limited chain reactions it did physically produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time--stretch&quot;&gt;Time &amp;amp; Stretch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project took at least a full-day, maybe two. Between filming, building, and editing, there was plenty of downtime and distractions, but it took awhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by trying out Adobe Premiere Rush recording feature in the app. Works pretty well, maybe even better than the built in video recorder? It also allowed me to instantly start building out the project in the app and syncs right to the Creative Suite. It also imports straight into Adobe Premiere for the finer editing. This was a first for using the process and it works wonders!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was moving through the project, I thought it might be clever to build in some shots that utilized zoom-like backgrounds. For this I needed to create a stage, in order to use Adobe Premieres keying effects. This was my second trial replacing backgrounds using the software, and this time I used the difference method. It requires the use of a still image of the background, new background, and then the video. I learned you can capture a still image frame right in Adobe. Setting up the stage was key to success and really taking control of the lighting - lessons learned from my first trial. I think it worked great this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project required lots of resizing and movement of videos. It also required each video to also have a still frame image to keep it on the screen after playback. When I started editing, I thought I considered every action that was going to be done, but I guess it’s the nature of editing that things may change. I zoomed in on all the frames, and this disrupted my still images - so lots of readjustments. I fine tuned my trimming abilities with each clip and I also figured out how to place the images on the screen by using some math and calculating some X, Y coordinates. It’s really about the small progressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all, I feel my Adobe Premiere Pro skill set solidifying and really getting a grasp on some basic effects and manipulation. Next up, strengthening my skills in on screen text (titles/credits).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recording: iPhone 12 mini&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recorded using Adobe Premiere Rush&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-production: Adobe Premiere Rush&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Production: Adobe Premiere Pro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attributions&quot;&gt;Attributions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/sb0Nt_Sk0bo&quot;&gt;@felipepelaquim&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/sr90ZsVcJjo&quot;&gt;Ovidiu Cozma&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/inVcSrX3qI8&quot;&gt;Roman Shilin&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/oJ4EMb9z7pU&quot;&gt;Massimiliano Morosinotto&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jason</name></author><category term="learnings" /><summary type="html">Assignment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Catfish Among Us</title><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/20/mini-storything-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Catfish Among Us" /><published>2021-03-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-03-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/20/mini-storything-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/20/mini-storything-4.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QUEST: You are the detective and the prosecutor.  Explore my backstory, find the clues and prepare your case to prosecute the catfish…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your prosecution should be like that of a trial lawyer.  Have your proof in order and present your case to the jury (the class).  You must make your case in the format of a digital-story.  You must convince us beyond a reasonable doubt that &lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_ is in fact, the catfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why yes, I believe I solved this case HG Wells, Author, Inventor, Futurist, Socialist. Using a variety of background information I found in Circle and some further digital tools, I think I have found PROOF of the imposter! I created a slideshow and narrated my process and deductions. I need to work on my prosecutorial narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began by clicking through the Circle site following all the #Catfish and looking into the posts, comments, spaces of the suspect’s list. I’ve also been observant of anything in Hypothesis. After putting together some additional leads I began putting together a collection of screen recordings, but then swung back to just screen captures - thinking about time. At this point, I decided to assemble a slide show, and walk through the evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my imagination, this would have taken place in a courtroom, and I would be addressing a jury OR perhaps in a detective format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time--stretch&quot;&gt;Time &amp;amp; Stretch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me 4-6 hours to click through all the evidence and assemble it into a slideshow and record a prosecutorial narrative. This was a one-shot video using Loom Screen and Video recorder, it was my first time using this tool in this manner. To stretch further, I would move this into a video editor (Premiere Pro) and see if I could bring my imagination to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;macOS: screen capture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Slides&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loom.com&quot;&gt;Loom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attributions&quot;&gt;Attributions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jason</name></author><category term="learnings" /><summary type="html">Assignment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Small changes lead to big improvements</title><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/thoughts/2021/03/15/accessability.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Small changes lead to big improvements" /><published>2021-03-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-03-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/thoughts/2021/03/15/accessability</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/thoughts/2021/03/15/accessability.html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had a sticky door lock? You know the ones where no matter how hard you try to turn the key, it just won’t turn. We’ve all been there and tried all sorts of maneuvers to get it to lock or unlock, jiggling the door, pushing and turning the lock, pulling and turning the lock. We might have even gone for a pair of pliers or a wrench and ended breaking the key! I remember walking my sister through how to unlock my door when they were housesitting for me. The lock was so tight she thought I had given her the wrong key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I follow many design blogs and came across an article about a simple redesign. It’s one of those simple iterations that make you think, why hasn’t this already been done? Let me introduce you to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nendo.jp/en/works/l-door-key/&quot;&gt;Nendo Key&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nendo.jp/wp/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/L-door_key12_akihiro_yoshida.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;an l shaped door key&quot; style=&quot;width:100%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Nendo's L-Door Key&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s one of those simple redesigns that potentially can improve life for many with disabilities. Think of those with poor vision no longer have to fumble with the key to find the right direction. Or those with mobility issues no longer having to struggle with the poor leverage of a standard key. Or any of us with a stubborn lock. And that’s what accessibility is all about, finding solutions that create better experiences for all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jason</name></author><category term="thoughts" /><category term="accessibility" /><summary type="html">Have you ever had a sticky door lock? You know the ones where no matter how hard you try to turn the key, it just won’t turn. We’ve all been there and tried all sorts of maneuvers to get it to lock or unlock, jiggling the door, pushing and turning the lock, pulling and turning the lock. We might have even gone for a pair of pliers or a wrench and ended breaking the key! I remember walking my sister through how to unlock my door when they were housesitting for me. The lock was so tight she thought I had given her the wrong key.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Perfect Fried Egg</title><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/13/mobile-media-project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Perfect Fried Egg" /><published>2021-03-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/13/mobile-media-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/13/mobile-media-project.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use a tool, format or combination from above and create a mobile media item. It can be a video, mobile webpage or mobile web app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topic: 3 Steps to success: Explain a process in 3 Steps. Examples include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating an agenda for the perfect meeting in 3 steps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to remember people’s names in 3 steps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bananas Foster in 3 steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no predefined time limit on this assignment. Each tool and format is different and the outcomes will vary. The time should be appropriate to that of the tool and the effectiveness of the final product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to think specifically about the mobile user, their experience and how media delivery and consumption may differ on a mobile device than a conventional desktop or laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learningexperience&quot;&gt;Learning/Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I moved into designing the webpage, I aimed to follow the layout of the well-known WikiHow pages - simple step-by-step instructions with images. I didn’t want to use “real-life” images, but rather, experiment with creating illustrated images. I kind of appreciate well-done illustrations on web pages and wanted to see if I could tackle some in this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it came time for creating, I took inspiration from a public television show - America’s Test Kitchen - and remixed a recipe and transformed screenshots into illustrations. Creating illustrations from photos was easier than expected; however, creating quality illustrations proves more difficult. When drafting out the copy, I initially produced something that resembled an essay and when migrating that to the web, it hit me, this copy wasn’t going to work. I was thinking about the mobile user at this moment and needed to adjust for them, scrolling, reading snippets of text, and glancing at pictures. So I paused and started reorganizing, breaking the text out into several, scannable layers, and on the final revision, I attempted to simplify the language more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a positive learning experience, and in the end, I had a funny insight about creating a three-step process. I intentionally was thinking of very simple tasks, processes, and procedures; but at the end of the day, I found myself having to redefine where the steps were to keep it within three for a simple process. So for a future project, I may go the other direction, and choose something extremely complicated and attempt to overly simplify it for fun and comic relief - It was one direction I considered at the start of this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;successes&quot;&gt;Successes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy web development as I believe it embodies the spirit of iteration in design, and that’s what I did with this project. Even though I did not set out to use Google Sites, at the end of the day it was a user-friendly tool that allowed me to easily make adjustments and edits to the webpage on the fly. I think the layout, design, and copy came together for a fluent mobile-first webpage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;struggles&quot;&gt;Struggles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I initially planned to write the HTML and CSS for the webpage myself, which then ultimately would morph into my basecamp; however, at the start of the unit, I also began the process of migrating to a newer mac. Long story short, moving from High Sierra to Catalina was more difficult than expected, especially when setting up a development environment. So I had to change course, enter Google Sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as easy as it was to use image tracing on a photograph to create a vector illustration and edit it, producing a quality illustration will take more time and experimentation. I also have a feeling that illustrating food was not the best subject for the first experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;macOS: Screen capture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Illustrator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attributions&quot;&gt;Attributions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americastestkitchen.com/videos/4634-perfect-fried-eggs&quot;&gt;Perfect Fried Eggs&lt;/a&gt; via Americas Test Kitchen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Illustrator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jason</name></author><category term="learnings" /><summary type="html">Assignment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Remixing with the Devil</title><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/13/mini-storything-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Remixing with the Devil" /><published>2021-03-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/13/mini-storything-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/03/13/mini-storything-3.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran across an isolated vocal track of David Lee Roth singing Running with the Devil, and couldn’t pass up using it in an assignment. Download the file and use the vocal track to create something unique. You can mash it up with movie clips, interviews, other songs, original video or audio that you record, or something completely different—just use some portion/portions of this track. Once you’ve done your mini-thing, post it to the # Mini-things channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first were given a pure vocal track, my mind went to making a video utilizing Adobe Character Animator. I’ve dabbled with this software in the past, and last time I learned that it can lip sync with audio tracks! And it’s pretty accurate. I thought this would free up some time to explore puppet animation and animation in general. Boy was I wrong! I’m not 100% on this, but I think Adobe is still in the process of moving from flash animation to HTML5 (?) and the animator may still be in beta. Also, the three programs were not necessarily playing nice with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began by downloading and then importing the audio into Adobe Character Animator and syncing it with my puppet easy enough! Then I moved onto some animations… In order to add additional animations, I had to move to Adobe Animate. I started with a quick tutorial, then made some animation, relatively quick. A challenge was making the circle hollow to allow the characters movements to pop out, but then also hiding the characters feet - that took a minute to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I imported both documents, the character and animation, into Adobe After Effects. It took me a minute to actually figure a workflow that Adobe accepted, this seems to be it. Merging the two documents and sound together was a bit of trial and error, like with most Adobe products, it’s familiar but the interface and function is just different enough to keep a person guessing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time--stretch&quot;&gt;Time &amp;amp; Stretch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I planned to pull this together in 2-4 hours, and I am embarrassed to say this 20 second animation took me 8 hours! I had to definitely flex through many frustrations, and had to restart several times because it was just easier to start from scratch than try to figure out what went wrong. I actually had more planned, and have a second character to walk in and continue the song, but I haven’t figured out how to get the limbs working correctly, yet. I’ll get there, though. I think it would be fun to actually be able to make animations proficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Animate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Character Animator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe After Effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attributions&quot;&gt;Attributions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;David Lee Roth: Running with the Devil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jason</name></author><category term="learnings" /><summary type="html">Assignment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Power of Yet</title><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/02/28/create-a-video.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Power of Yet" /><published>2021-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/02/28/create-a-video</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/02/28/create-a-video.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time to produce a video. It will be no less than 3 minutes and no longer than 5 minutes. Projects under or over the assigned time limit will be subject to point deductions. A big part of this unit will expose you to the aspects and challenges of video production and some of the biggest challenges can be lighting, shooting, importing and editing video. You don’t have to make an appearance but I do expect the project to comprise of some video content that has been shot from a camera and edited by you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topic: Let’s take the mind away from academic thinking and get a little creative. For this video project you will need to choose a phrase or verse from a song and do one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deconstruct it,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Act it out / illustrate it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interpret it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learningexperience&quot;&gt;Learning/Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a challenging project but in a good way. I misread the topic for the assignment and started planning around a phrase - I missed the relationship to a song; therefore, I initially had planned a video around an introduction to Growth Mindset. This in itself was a good learning experience because as I was planning, I kept realizing how much I rely on interaction or interactivity when designing instructional materials. This had me going back and revising and thinking about how I could adapt the idea for an asynchronous video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as I said I had misread the topic and missed the song component - whoops. I noticed this about a week ago when I was reviewing the project guidelines about to record, silly me. So, I then freaked out and then started revising… I ended up sticking with the same theme but adjusted everything for a song relating to the Growth Mindset. I had a couple of variations and songs picked out, but since they are lesser-known - or not at all - this created a new challenge. I ended up remixing around a YouTube: Sesame Street song, it has been sampled and cut up, but I would think this project falls in the grey area for fair use/education copyright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;successes&quot;&gt;Successes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, I pulled together a video, incorporating a word or phrase in a song, around the theme of Growth Mindset. As you can see, I took the creative piece and tried to have some fun with the video production at the end of the day. This is not what I might have pulled together if I was thinking strictly of an educational video production, which is a good learning experience for future reflections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would consider that I was able to incorporate “draw my life” concepts that I was watching as part of this unit a success. It was surprisingly difficult to pull off - but it did allow me to practice audio recording as well as experiment with a new type of video production. I’m starting to feel comfortable with basic video editing, so I tried to push my abilities boundaries, for better or worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;struggles&quot;&gt;Struggles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh man, did I ever struggle? First with my poor reading skills. But then I struggled to pull my vision together while editing the video. One thing I am very disappointed with was I was not able to pull the background out of my layered video clips. I have no idea why? I watched several tutorials pull it off successfully and I did everything the same, but no matter the method I tried, it never quite worked. Either the layered video became a ghost, or the color of the layered video became severely off tone. I tried so many techniques and was too far in it to turn around. So, unfortunately, I had to settle for a ghostly result with background fragments. It could be my lighting during recording, but it also could have been a setting on my recording device. Either way, I will try the method again in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found the “draw your life” handwriting or drawing to be a challenge too. The tutorials I watched made it sound so easy to adjust the timing of the video to the words - it is not. You also have one shot to capture it… I guess that’s no different than recording anything else, whereas, if there’s an error you have to go back and reshoot the whole scene. I found one at the end - during export - but correcting it would have meant I had to reshoot the beginning too since I was building off of an earlier shot. I also think the original audio is out of sync - I thought it was just the lag in rendering :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all, this was a challenging and rewarding experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone 12 mini&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Premiere Pro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attributions&quot;&gt;Attributions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/XLeUvZvuvAs&quot;&gt;Power of Yet&lt;/a&gt; via YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jason</name></author><category term="learnings" /><summary type="html">Assignment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vintage poster</title><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/02/27/mid-storything-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vintage poster" /><published>2021-02-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-02-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/02/27/mid-storything-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/02/27/mid-storything-2.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remix a historic poster, advertisement or magazine cover with a modern context.
#graphic-design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requirements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Original material must come from the public domain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide context. Tell us any backstory, irony, or nuance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include a side-by-side comparison to the original image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not initially set out to create this postcard… but after I planned, scripted, and started recording a “Draw My Life” I changed my direction. I felt a need to create something exposing Denver’s Homelessness problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea why this is not being reported more widely, or at least I have not heard or seen any news about the growing number of homeless in Denver County. It is saddening, and during the cold snap and snow storm I watched people cycle through and warm themselves in my buildings entry way - in hourly rotations. I even think some were sleeping in our entryway and possibly hallway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to think to myself, are they trespassing? Should I care? Should I call someone and report this? Or just forgive them for being cold human beings and let them have a place to warm themselves… I chose to forgive their trespassing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this poster is made to drive awareness of this growing issue. There are literally full blocks of camps, and not just one. It is normal for me to pass two or three encampments within a mile walk/bike ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every month or so, it appears homeless sweeps occur. Where basically the homeless are displaced from their homeless encampments. It’s just silly to move them from one block to the next, without providing any support. There really has to be something more that the city can be doing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In gathering information, I came across this recent article published January 26, 2021 from Colorado Politics, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coloradopolitics.com/denver/new-report-shows-denver-region-s-homeless-population-is-significantly-greater-more-racially-inequitable-than/article_e5cb915c-0cda-11eb-83e5-e7da9c107303.html&quot;&gt;New report shows Denver region’s homeless population is ‘significantly’ greater, more racially inequitable than previously estimated&lt;/a&gt;. The opening line of the article pretty much says it all, “The number of people experiencing homelessness in Denver is vastly higher than previously estimated, a new report by the Metro Denver Homeless Initiative revealed Monday.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I shifted my focus to this project, I knew I wanted to create something relating to a travel advertisement, but instead of featuring high end hotels or beautiful scenery, I was going to show homelessness in the streets of Denver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started searching the public domain. The search took an hour or two, it wasn’t easy finding the source material. And once I did stumble onto the postcard (original) it took some time to figure out if it was indeed in the public domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have often thought of recording or photographing some of the scenes I see around weekly, but haven’t. So for this project I needed to find additional images… and surprisingly Unsplash had some. To include the images I needed to manipulate them and remove the backgrounds. I know photoshop can do this, but I don’t know how to do it efficiently or well, or maybe at all. But before starting this project, I spent time in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so/d0376ca12f8e419d9d6558ab378c4bea?v=c089e77ea4b846928316e9535f805138&quot;&gt;Digital MakerSpace Tools&lt;/a&gt; and remember coming across a background removal tool. It works really well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My whole process in Adobe Photoshop was a process of trial and error. I know what it’s capable of doing, but have never really used it - I follow the updates to Adobe tools across their creative cloud line. I’ve used other Adobe products and that knowledge sort of transferred over, but Photoshop is just weird and foreign. So trial and error mostly guided me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I touched every tool in the interface, spot healing and the smudge tool was very useful for this, as were the effects. I dropped all colors from my remixed images and adjusted them to black and white for contrast and emphasis. I used clip-masking around every image to layer them into the original, tip: original image goes above the clip area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know photoshop has a font matching tool? Neither did… and it was one of many things that I learned googling while piecing this together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time--stretch&quot;&gt;Time / Stretch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project took a full day AKA 8 hours. Not including the time that I spent thinking about the issue/postcard. I would say my time was equally split between finding public domain images, googling how-to do stuff, doing stuff, and touching up the finer details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stretched to pull together a vision, and I feel good about getting it onto the page. I stretched and flexed skills from other Adobe products and stumbled around in photoshop. I think using the background removal tool really saved me a lot of time, effort, confusion, so useful. I pushed myself to remove the mountains and manipulate an image of a homeless encampment in its place. That actually might have taken an additional hour or more…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.remove.bg&quot;&gt;RemoveBG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attributions&quot;&gt;Attributions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Curt Teich Postcard Archives Digital Collection (Newberry Library) - &lt;a href=&quot;https://collections.carli.illinois.edu/digital/collection/nby_teich/id/7279/rec/3&quot;&gt;156, Greeting you from the Denver, The Mile High City, Where the West is at its Best&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;History Colorado - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.historycolorado.org/story/2019/07/24/wish-you-were-here-colorful-colorado-postcards-and-visual-history-colorado&quot;&gt;“Wish You Were Here” in Colorful Colorado: Postcards and the Visual History of Colorado&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Image: D) Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/J5EUUY7SuLk&quot;&gt;Ilse Orsel&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Image: E) Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/lQ2BzDNmnHE&quot;&gt;John Moeses&lt;/a&gt; Bauan on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Image: N) Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/rbz1hVh7_LM&quot;&gt;Jon Tyson&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Image: V) Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/q2NiO7JvN2A&quot;&gt;Jean-Luc Benazet&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Image: E) Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/ajzN2AYNi1U&quot;&gt;Jon Tyson&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Image: R) Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/lQ2BzDNmnHE&quot;&gt;Steve Knutson&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Image: Tent City) Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=77434473&quot;&gt;NeoBatfreak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;, via Wikimedia CommonsPhoto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jason</name></author><category term="learnings" /><summary type="html">Assignment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Design Your Tribes Ink</title><link href="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/02/20/mini-storything-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design Your Tribes Ink" /><published>2021-02-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-02-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/02/20/mini-storything-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://j.sohvi.design/basecamp/v1/learnings/2021/02/20/mini-storything-2.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re part of a tribe, show some pride by designing your own tattoo that is symbolic of your tribe’s culture. Step 1: Pick out an icon or set of icons at the Noun Project Website and remix it into your own unique design and post it to the # Mini-things channel. Here’s the catch, don’t let the other teams know your team’s name. Step 2: Try to guess what the other team’s name is through astute analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, a remix… I choose to export SVG from the noun project and began in Canva. As I started to layer icons, I needed to be able to hide pieces of them… I tried hiding things with boxes in Canva, but that quickly became unreasonable. So, I searched out another editor… and found &lt;a href=&quot;https://boxy-svg.com/&quot;&gt;Boxy SVG Editor&lt;/a&gt;. It is very similar to Adobe Illustrator; however, some aspects seemed simplified - in a good way… so this worked great for remixing the icons from the noun project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually found many icons representing my tribe - by name - but I selected alternative icons to not give anything away in the Attribution text. I spent a couple hours searching &amp;amp; remixing together icons to tell a little visual story. The whole mini-thing was created using only remixed icons. I might have started having to much fun stitching together the icons… Can you guess my tribes name?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time--stretch&quot;&gt;Time / Stretch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boxy-svg.com/&quot;&gt;Boxy SVG Editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com&quot;&gt;The Noun Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attributions&quot;&gt;Attributions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/search/?q=square&amp;amp;i=987124&quot;&gt;square&lt;/a&gt; by Vladimir Belochkin from the Noun Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/search/?q=fog&amp;amp;i=680139&quot;&gt;fog&lt;/a&gt; by Iulia Ardeleanu from the Noun Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/search/?q=future&amp;amp;i=2525275&quot;&gt;Future&lt;/a&gt; by fae frey from the Noun Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/search/?q=bolt&amp;amp;i=3182471&quot;&gt;bolt&lt;/a&gt; by Gajah Mada Studio from the Noun Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/search/?q=clock+tower&amp;amp;i=1153261&quot;&gt;clock tower&lt;/a&gt; by Creaticca Creative Agency from the Noun Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/search/?q=intersection+lines&amp;amp;i=3169292&quot;&gt;intersection&lt;/a&gt; by Zach Bogart from the Noun Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/search/?q=fast+car&amp;amp;i=1266564&quot;&gt;fast car&lt;/a&gt; by Nikita Kozin from the Noun Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/search/?q=dog&amp;amp;i=2755593&quot;&gt;Dog&lt;/a&gt; by Tauficon from the Noun Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/search/?q=scientist&amp;amp;i=3166564&quot;&gt;Scientist&lt;/a&gt; by Flatart from the Noun Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jason</name></author><category term="learnings" /><summary type="html">Assignment</summary></entry></feed>